http://www.ipu.org/privacy-statement

Subscribe to our newsletter
Our impactOur impactThe IPU facilitates parliamentary diplomacy and empowers parliaments and parliamentarians to promote peace, democracy and sustainable development around the world.Read moreMoreStrong parliamentsWe help strengthen parliaments to make them more effective and representative.
Gender equalityWe work to increase women’s representation in parliament and empower women MPs.
Human rightsWe defend the human rights of parliamentarians and help them uphold the rights of all.
PeacebuildingWe help parliaments fight terrorism, cyber warfare and the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction.
Parliamentary dialogueWe create the global space for parliamentary diplomacy, dialogue and networking.
Youth empowermentWe encourage youth participation in parliaments and empower young MPs.
Sustainable developmentWe support parliaments in implementing the SDGs with a particular focus on health and climate change.
Global governanceWe bring a parliamentary dimension to United Nations processes to ensure international commitments become national realities.
ParliamentsNational ParliamentsEvery country in the world has some form of parliament. Parliamentary systems fall into two categories: bicameral and unicameral. Out of 193 countries in the world, 79 are bicameral and 114 are unicameral, making a total of 272 chambers of parliament with over 46,000 members of parliament. IPU membership is made up of 179 national parliaments. Discover the world's nationalRead moreSee all parliamentsFind a national parliamentParliamentsAll parliamentsAfghanistanAlbaniaAlgeriaAndorraAngolaAntigua And BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBhutanBolivia (Plurinational State Of)Bosnia And HerzegovinaBotswanaBrazilBrunei DarussalamBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCabo VerdeCambodiaCameroonCanadaCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaColombiaComorosCongoCosta RicaCroatiaCubaCyprusCzech RepublicCôte d'IvoireDemocratic People's Republic Of KoreaDemocratic Republic of the CongoDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEswatiniEthiopiaFijiFinlandFranceGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGreeceGrenadaGuatemalaGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHondurasHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIran (Islamic Republic Of)IraqIrelandIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiKuwaitKyrgyzstanLao People's Democratic RepublicLatviaLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMauritaniaMauritiusMexicoMicronesia (Federated States Of)MonacoMongoliaMontenegroMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNorth MacedoniaNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestinePanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPolandPortugalQatarRepublic Of KoreaRepublic Of MoldovaRomaniaRussian FederationRwandaSaint Kitts And NevisSaint LuciaSaint Vincent and the GrenadinesSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome And PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSouth SudanSpainSri LankaSudanSurinameSwedenSwitzerlandSyrian Arab RepublicTajikistanThailandTimor-LesteTogoTongaTrinidad And TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTuvaluUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited Republic of TanzaniaUnited States of AmericaUruguayUzbekistanVanuatuVenezuela (Bolivarian Republic Of)Viet NamYemenZambiaZimbabweThe Swiss National Council © The Swiss ParliamentStrong parliamentsWe help strengthen parliaments to make them more representative and effective..Read moreOur support for parliamentsGeopolitical groupsAfrican groupArab GroupAsia-Pacific GroupEurasia GroupGRULAC (Group of Latin America and the Caribbean)Twelve Plus GroupUnaffiliatedEventsVirtual eventThird Expert Roundtable on the Common Principles for Support to ParliamentsChallenges and opportunities in parliamentary monitoring and evaluationRead more09/12/2020Events and meetingsFuture eventsPast eventsEventsThroughout the year, the IPU and its Members organize many events for parliamentarians to exchange good practices, acquire the latest information and identify avenues for action.Read moreGet involvedKnowledgeKnowledgeThe IPU has been collecting data on parliaments since its inception in 1889, including information on women’s participation in politics since 1945. In this section, discover the IPU's knowledge bank for and about parliaments.Read moreRead moreDiscover the IPU's resourcesPublicationsOur library of essential resources for parliamentsParline DataYour one-stop-shop for data for and about national parliamentsWomen in politicsLatest data and reports about women's participation in politicsIPU Innovation TrackerRecent innovations in the way parliaments do their work
About the IPU
About us
Genesis of the IPU
Structure and governance
Members
Statutes and Rules of the IPU
Gender-equal IPU
Association of Secretaries General of Parliaments
Privacy Statement
The IPU is committed to respecting the privacy of the people it engages with. This privacy statement explains how we may collect and process your information as a result of your visit to IPU websites www.ipu.org or data.ipu.org.
In general, you can browse IPU websites without telling us who you are or revealing personally identifiable information.
However some anonymous information is collected by a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") to help analyze the use of the website. The information generated by the cookies about the use of the website - standard internet log information (including your IP address) and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form - is transmitted to and stored by Google. We anonymize your IP address before sending it to Google.
In accordance with its Privacy Shield Certification, Google declares that it complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework. Google may transfer the information collected by Google Analytics to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. According to Google Analytics terms of service, Google will not associate the data subject IP address with any other data held by Google.
The IPU collects and publishes parliamentary data on its websites, including personal information about parliamentarians such as their name, gender and age. This information is made available either by consent or by publicly available sources.
IPU’s mailing list
Opting in to the IPU’s mailing list means providing with us, at a minimum, your name, your email address and your language preference.
As a result, you will receive emails or newsletters from the IPU about parliaments, the state of democracy generally, and the IPU’s activities.
We do not use your data for direct marketing of goods or services to subscribers.
MailChimp, a third party service, manages the subscriptions and distribution of IPU newsletters. We encourage you to read and ask questions regarding their privacy policy before you choose to provide information about yourself.
You can change your mind at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any email you receive from us, or by contacting us at press@ipu.org.
The IPU tries to protect the security and integrity of the information you provide us by implementing technical safeguards designed to protect against loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. However, due to the open and global nature of the internet, these safeguards are not a guarantee. The IPU assumes no responsibility for guaranteeing the security of information.
Notification of changes
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time and encourage you to stay informed by reviewing updates posted here.
External and third-party links
The IPU websites contain links to external or third-party websites. These websites are not related to the IPU or under our control. The IPU is therefore not responsible for the privacy or security of personal information which may be collected or processed via external or third-party websites or used by their owners. The appearance of such external or third-party links on the website does not represent the IPU’s endorsement of, or affiliation with, them. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of external or third-party websites.
Privileges and immunities
Nothing in or related to this privacy statement may be construed as a waiver, express or implied, of the privileges and immunities accorded to the IPU.
Last update: 13 September 2018
Our work
Strong parliaments
Gender equality
Parliamentary dialogue
Human rights
Sustainable development
Peacebuilding
Commission on the Status of Women (CSW)
Committee to Promote Respect for International Humanitarian Law
Advisory Group on Health
Forum of Women Parliamentarians
Forum of Young Parliamentarians
High-Level Advisory Group on Countering Terrorism and Violent Extremism
GRULAC (Group of Latin America and the Caribbean)
